

Skills

Top 1% Contributor on Stack Overflow. Exceptional Achievements in the **Programming Community**

JavaScript/TypeScript (> 9 years)

Web, Desktop, and Mobile Applications (React, Vue, Angular, Svelte)

*** * * * ***

C# Development (> 20 years)

Web, Desktop, Server, and Mobile **Applications**

APIs (> 15 years)

GraphQL & REST APIs *** * * * ***

SQL Databases (> 9 years)

PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MariaDB, MySQL, SQLite

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$

NoSQL Databases (> 15 years) MongoDB, Firebase, Redis

DevOps (> 9 years)

GitLab $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$

Serverless (> 9 years) AWS Lambda, Google Cloud Functions,

Azure Functions

Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub Actions,

Edge Functions & Edge Runtime $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$

Edge Computing (> 1 year)

Spoken Languages

German

English

Denis Knaack

Software Development & Consulting

& +49 170 5867448 • @ denis@knaack.it • ♂ https://www.knaack.it

Profiles

in /denisknaack

/dknaack

/knaackee

Okt. 2003 – Jan. 2008

Jan. 2008 – Apr. 2011

Nov. 2012 - Feb. 2015

Steinberg am See, DE

2000 - 2003

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

Figma

NodeJS / Typescript

Typescript

React Native

NodeJS / Typescript

Regensburg, DE

Throughout my career, I have worked with various programming languages, tools, and services. My passion for technology motivated me to continually evolve. Customers appreciate my ability to integrate new technologies and provide solutions that often exceed their objectives.

business life. I use these experiences to advise teams and develop strategies that align with business goals. In this role, I was also involved in the creation and acquisition of a software patent.

As the CTO and co-founder of a startup, I gained valuable insights into

Professional Experience GoNamic GmbH

Manager Software Development Regensburg, DE

SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG Manager Software Development

Regensburg, DE Apr. 2011 - Nov. 2012 SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG

Senior Manager Software Development Omniga GmbH & Co. KG

Software Development Professional Regensburg, DE KNAACK.IT Feb. 2015 - heute

Education

Fintech Startup

Visa Policy Update

GraphQL Backend

Plug-In System

Auto-Updater

TypeScript.

UI / UX

GraphQL Backend

Chrome Extension

TypeScript.

COVID Scanner App

BSZ Matthäus Runtinger BSIII Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung (IT Specialist in

Software Development & Consulting

Application Development)

Projects (Excerpt)

Development of backend solutions and APIs for a fintech startup, utilizing C# and Microsoft SQL Database.

Automated Email Dispatch (Implementation of Automated Invoice Email C# Distribution) Implementation of an automated system for emailing invoices, developed in

Implementation of new requirements for visa payment processing using C#.

Website Relaunch

Redevelopment and modernization of a website using C#. **Password Validation**

Transition from plain text passwords to hashed and salted passwords,

implemented in C#. Mailgun Integration

Implementation and documentation. Consulting GraphQL

Advising a development team on GraphQL implementation and best practices.

Development of a sample implementation for a GraphQL backend using NodeJS and TypeScript.

NNTP Client

Development of an NNTP client using C#.

Enhancement of a Windows client with a plug-in system, developed in C#.

Implementation of an automatic update system for a Windows application.

Creation of an app for scanning and displaying information from QR codes, developed with React Native.

Marketing Website React / Typescript

Al Chatbot React / Typescript

Development of a website for a mid-sized company, utilizing React and

React and TypeScript.

Design and integration of an AI chatbot based on ChatGPT, implemented using

Creation and presentation of a user interface for a web application using Figma.

Automatic Update Feature for Electron App **NodeJS**

Development of a self-updating mechanism tailored for an Electron application, utilizing NodeJS.

Development of an API with integration to a PostgreSQL database, implemented using NodeJS and TypeScript.

Development of a Chrome extension with ChatGPT integration, implemented in

Outlook Plugin Typescript

Creation of a plugin for easier management of filters and folders in Outlook, developed in TypeScript.

NodeJS / Electron / Typescript **Desktop Client** Development of a cross-platform client for Windows, Mac, and Linux for

processing and analyzing AAF files, using NodeJS, Electron, TypeScript, and C#.

CI / CD Github Actions Creation and implementation of a Continuous Integration and Continuous

Delivery (CI/CD) process for a team with various projects, utilizing GitHub Actions. React / Typescript **Progressive Web App**

Development of a Progressive Web App (installable, offline-ready) with

features including authentication, email sending, and more, built using React and TypeScript.